[
    
    Fully featured, collaborative document editing](https://www.collaboraoffice.com/collabora-online/)[
    
    Same great features on your desktop](https://www.collaboraoffice.com/collabora-office/)[
    
    Try the development edition for free](https://www.collaboraoffice.com/code/)
    
    [for iOS and Android
    -------------------
    
    ](https://www.collaboraoffice.com/collabora-office-android-ios/)[for Education
    -------------
    
    ](https://www.collaboraoffice.com/collabora-online-for-education/)
    
    [Pricing
    -------](https://www.collaboraoffice.com/subscriptions/)
    
    Collabora Online apps
    ---------------------
    
    [
    
    Writer
    ------](https://www.collaboraoffice.com/writer/)[
    
    Calc
    ----](https://www.collaboraoffice.com/calc/)
    
    [
    
    Impress
    -------](https://www.collaboraoffice.com/impress/)[
    
    Draw
    ----](https://www.collaboraoffice.com/draw/)
    
    [
    
    Collabora Online Controller
    ---------------------------
    
    For large deployments](https://www.collaboraoffice.com/collabora-online-controller/)
    
    [
    
    Fully featured, collaborative document editing](https://www.collaboraoffice.com/collabora-online/)[
    
    Same great features on your desktop](https://www.collaboraoffice.com/collabora-office/)[
    
    Try the development edition for free](https://www.collaboraoffice.com/code/)[
    
    Collabora Online  
    Controller
    -----------------------------
    
    For large deployments](https://www.collaboraoffice.com/collabora-online-controller/)[Pricing
    -------](https://www.collaboraoffice.com/subscriptions/)
    
    [for iOS and Android
    -------------------](https://www.collaboraoffice.com/collabora-office-android-ios/)[for Education
    -------------](https://www.collaboraoffice.com/collabora-online-for-education/)

    Partners
    --------
    
    [Find a partner
    --------------](https://new.collaboraoffice.com/partners/)[Become a partner
    ----------------](https://www.collaboraoffice.com/become-partner/)[Partner portal
    --------------](https://www.collaboraoffice.com/partner-client-portal/)
    
    Integrations
    ------------
    
    [Find out more
    -------------](https://www.collaboraoffice.com/integrations/)
    
    Featured Partners
    -----------------

    Featured Integrations
    ---------------------

    [About Us
    --------
    
    Meet the team making the magic happen](https://www.collaboraoffice.com/about-us/)[Careers
    -------
    
    Find out about current vacancies](https://www.collaboraoffice.com/careers/)
    
    [Testimonials
    ------------](https://www.collaboraoffice.com/testimonials/)[White Papers & Case Studies
    ---------------------------](https://www.collaboraoffice.com/case-studies/)[FAQs
    ----](https://www.collaboraoffice.com/faqs/)

    [THE #cool\_dev COMMUNITY
    ------------------------](https://www.collaboraoffice.com/resources/)[Collabora Online Forum
    ----------------------](https://forum.collaboraonline.com/)[Collabora Online Translations
    -----------------------------](https://collaboraonline.github.io/post/translate/)[Built on LibreOffice
    --------------------](https://www.collaboraoffice.com/built-on-libreoffice/)

    Consultancy
    -----------
    
    [Tailor-made consultancy from the leaders in LibreOffice development](https://www.collaboraoffice.com/consultancy/)[Engineering Support](https://www.collaboraoffice.com/engineering-support/)[Events
    ------
    
    Find out where we’re going, and where we’ve been!](https://www.collaboraoffice.com/events/)
    
    [Accessibility
    -------------](https://www.collaboraoffice.com/accessibility/)[Security
    --------](https://www.collaboraoffice.com/security/)

X

Privacy Notice
--------------

Privacy Notice V1.2
===================

_Date of issue: 05/10/2024_

Company
-------

Collabora Productivity is a division of Collabora, the global software consultancy dedicated to providing benefits of Open Source to the commercial world, specializing in mobile, automotive and consumer electronics industries. The headquarter of Collabora Productivity is in the Platinum Building St. John’s Innovation Park, Cambridge, United Kingdom.

Collabora Productivity provides Collabora Online, the feature rich and compatible open source solution for editing and collaboration, and a range of other products and consulting to enterprise and government. Powered by the largest team of certified LibreOffice engineers in the world, it is a leading contributor to the LibreOffice codebase and community

Our Cookies Policy
------------------

By using this website you are consenting to our use of the cookies outlined below. We are not responsible for the use or data collected in any cookies set by third parties. Details of how to control and delete cookies are listed below.

Cookies are small text files that are placed on your computer by websites that you visit. They are widely used in order to make websites work, or work more efficiently, as well as to provide information to the owners of the site. Cookies are not programs and therefore cannot contain viruses or other malicious software. They are purely a string of text and numbers. This website uses cookies as outlined below to help tailor and make our website and your browsing experience better! Your personal data will not be stored or processed for sinister purposes please rest assured!

How we process personal data
----------------------------

We collect personal contact data via the contact form placed in our website when attending conferences or events. We collect data for marketing and sales purposes.

Depending on the nature of the interactions, certain users maybe asked to provide personally-identifying information. An example of this is when we ask for visitors who request a demo at collaboraoffice.com to provide personal data such as name or email address. Collabora does not disclose personally-identifying information other than as described below.

We collect personal data from User’s Feedback CSV file. Collabora’s websites have an option for the users to leave their feedback on the product. The main purpose to collect users’ feedback is to improve the product for them. Here users asked to provide personal information but they can refuse to supply personally identifying information other than just leaving their feedback.

The data we collect
-------------------

We collect and process the following data.

| Purpose | Data Collected |
| --- | --- |
| Business contract | Full name, email address, phone numbers |
| Shipping equipment | Full name, business address, phone numbers. This could be non-business phone numbers depending on the kind of address the equipment is being shipped to |
| Source code repositories and bug trackers | Full name, username, such as a Github ID |
| Invoicing | Email address, business address, bank details |
| Leads and business development | Full name, email address, and phone number |
| Users Feedback Collection | Full name, email address, and phone number |

How do we protect Certain Personally-Identifying Information?
-------------------------------------------------------------

Collabora discloses potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information only to those of its employees, contractors, affiliates, and partners that;

1. need to know that information in order to process it on Collabora’s behalf or to provide services available at Collabora’s websites, or to connect you to a partner’s services.
2. that have agreed not to disclose it to others.

Some of those employees, contractors and affiliated organizations may be located outside of your home country; by using Collabora’s websites, you consent to the transfer of such information to them. Collabora will not rent or sell potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information to anyone. Other than to its employees, contractors, affiliates, and partners, as described above, Collabora discloses potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information only in response to a witness summons, court order, or other governmental request, or when Collabora believes in good faith that disclosure is reasonably necessary to protect the property or rights of Collabora, third parties or the public at large.

If you send us a request (for example via a support email or via one of our feedback mechanisms), we reserve the right to publish it in order to help us clarify or respond to your request or to help us support other users. Collabora takes all measures reasonably necessary to protect against the unauthorized access, use, alteration or destruction of potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information.

Do we use ‘cookies’?
--------------------

A cookie is a string of information that a website stores on a visitor’s computer, and that the visitor’s browser provides to the website each time the visitor returns. Collabora uses cookies to help Collabora identify and track visitors, their usage of Collabora website, and their website access preferences. Collabora visitors who do not wish to have cookies placed on their computers and do not wish to have their browsing profiled or to have custom content tailored to them, should set their browsers to refuse cookies before using Collabora’s websites, with the drawback that certain features of Collabora’s websites may not function properly without the aid of cookies.

First party cookies
-------------------

#### Anonymous analytics cookies – \[Google Analytics\] (“\_ga, \_gat”)

Google Analytics is a system used by many websites to record anonymous information about who visits a website. Google set two different cookies with expiry dates ranging from 10 minutes to 2 years. These cookies are used mainly to differentiate between first-time visitors to a website and repeat visitors. They do not contain any personally identifiable information. You can find out more about how Google use cookies at http://www.google.com/intl/en/analytics/privacyoverview.html. You can also review Google’s Privacy Policy on analytics here [http://www.google.com/analytics/learn/privacy.html](http://www.google.com/analytics/learn/privacy.html). You can opt out of Google Analytics on all sites by installing this browser plugin [http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout](http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout).

#### Matomo analytics cookies (“\_pk\_id, \_pk\_ses, \_pk\_ref, \_pf\_testcookie”)

Matomo is an open source web analytics platform. A web analytics platform is used by a website owner in order to measure, collect, analyse and report visitors data for purposes of understanding and optimizing their website.  

#### PHPSESSID cookie (“PHPSESSID”)

This is a session ID cookie which is stored to allow the CMS system which renders each page on this website, know which pages it has rendered during your browsing session. It stores a random number ID which has nothing to do with you or your browsing behavior.

#### Mautic cookies (“mautic\_refer\_id, mautic\_session\_id, mautic\_session\_name”)

These cookies are used to detect how visitors engaged with the website, in order to improve the information we provide on the website or through marketing campaigns. Visitors that choose not to engage with any website form or email-link will remain anonymous.

#### Controlling or deleting cookies

Depending on which web browser you use it is possible to control how cookies are used or to delete existing cookies from your computer. You can find instructions on how to control the use of cookies, or remove cookies from your computer at [https://www.aboutcookies.org.uk/managing-cookies](https://www.aboutcookies.org.uk/managing-cookies).

All modern browsers allow you to change your cookie settings. These settings will typically be found in the ‘options’ or ‘preferences’ menu of your browser. In order to understand these settings, the following links may be helpful, otherwise, you should use the ‘Help’ option in your browser for more details.

Please remember that if you delete or restrict cookies from this website you may not be able to experience the full benefit of some of the features and services this website has to offer.

Online Demos
------------

Our online demos will allow you to try out Collabora Online. You can upload documents, share them and edit them (alone or collaboratively). But before you start to upload files, please keep the following in mind:

* Don’t upload any personal data, private or sensitive information. Sessions and data may be logged for performance and testing reasons.
* This demo is running on our servers, which will be upgraded fairly regularly. This allows you to try out the latest edition, but on the other hand, can result in data loss.
* The service may disappear at any time.

Transfer of data to third parties
---------------------------------

Our servers are located in the UK and Canada which are considered to already be bound by GDPR/DPA legislation. On these servers we host email, CRM (customer data management), Phabricator (task management system), Mattermost (internal messaging), Gitlab(source code management) and document storage.

We may occasionally use Google Docs and Hangouts to share information. This data transfer to Google servers in the United States of America is protected by Standard Contractural Clauses.

Data related to invoicing is processed by a 3rd party whose data servers are located in the United States of America. This data transfer is protected by Standard Contractual Clauses.

These 3rd parties are service providers (data processors) to Collabora and we only share information with them as part of regular business activities. In no case, does Collabora sell customer data of any kind.

Retention Period
----------------

* Collabora will keep all project related data for a period of 12 years from project completion.
* Personal data entered into a git repository will be retained permanently.
* Collabora will keep all financial records from the project for a period of 12 years from project completion year.
* Collabora will keep data collected via contact forms in our website for 3 years.
* Data collected from events, and trade shows, will be retained for a period of 6 months.

Your Rights
-----------

We operate under the UK Data Protection Act (DPA) 2018 which encompasses the EU GDPR regulation.

The data protection laws require us to make sure that the personal data we hold is:

1. processed lawfully, fairly and in a transparent manner;
2. collected for specified, explicit and legitimate purposes and not further processed in a manner that is incompatible with those purposes;
3. adequate, relevant and limited to what is necessary in relation to the purposes for which they are processed;
4. accurate and where necessary kept up to date;
5. kept for no longer than is necessary for the purposes for which the personal data are processed;
6. processed in a manner that ensures appropriate security of the personal data, including protection against unauthorized or unlawful processing and against accidental loss, destruction or damage, using appropriate technical or organizational measures.

To exercise any of the rights listed below, please contact us using data@collabora.com. In order to process your request, we may need to verify your identity for your security. In such cases, we will need you to respond with proof of your identity.

1. The right to access personal data we hold on you. At any point you can contact us to request the personal data we hold on you as well as why we have that personal data, who has access to the personal data and where we obtained the personal data from. Once we have received your request and verified who you are we will usually respond within one month. There are no fees or charges for the first request but additional requests for the same personal data or requests which are manifestly unfounded or excessive may be subject to an administrative fee.
2. The right to correct and update the personal data we hold on you.
3. The right to object to processing of your personal data or to restrict it to certain purposes only. You have the right to request that we stop processing your personal data or ask us to restrict processing. Upon receiving the request we will contact you and let you know if we are able to comply or if we have a legal obligation to continue to process your data.
4. The right to withdraw your consent to the processing at any time for any processing of data to which consent was obtained.
5. The right to request portability of data. You can request that personal data you have provided which is based on consent or for the performance of a contract and that that has been carried out by automated means be provided to you in a structured and machine-readable format.
6. The right to object. You can object to your personal data being used where the legal basis is legitimate interest or public interest or is being used for direct marketing.
7. The right to not be subject to decision based solely on automated processing.
8. The right to lodge a complaint with the Information Commissioner’s Office. You can contact the Information Commissioner’s Office on 0303 123 1113 or via email \[ \] or at the Information Commissioner’s Office, Wycliffe House, Water Lane, Wilmslow, Cheshire SK9 5AF. Alternatively, please contact the relevant supervisory body for the country you are resident.

* * *

#### Changes from [v1.1](https://www.collaboraoffice.com/privacy-notice-v1_1/)

Added Matomo tracking details.

Collabora Productivity Ltd © 2024 All Rights Reserved.

Learn how we helped 100 top brands gain success
-----------------------------------------------

Full Name 

Phone 

Email 

Send
